http://www.literacytrust.org.uk/information/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
See all in Information
We take your privacy very seriously. This privacy policy (together with our terms and conditions) explains what information the National Literacy Trust may collect about you, how we will use it, and the steps we will take to ensure it is kept secure.The information we collectWe collect information about you when you become a member, take part in our programmes or events, make use of our other services (including this website), volunteer, donate or support our work in other ways. We also collect information when you voluntarily complete surveys or evaluation activity, and participate in competitions. Website usage information is collected using cookies.The information we collect includes your name, address, place of work, job title, email address and phone number. We will collect this through your use of our website, as well as direct communication through phone calls, emails, social media or in person.How we use your informationWe collect information about you to manage your membership, deliver programmes in partnership with you, process orders, manage donations and events and, if you agree, to email you about other products and services we think may be of interest to you.We use your information collected by our website to personalise your repeat visits and allow you to access and update your account easily.We will only use your information for the purposes for which it was obtained. We never pass on your personal information to any other organisations unless you have specifically agreed at the point of giving your information, or it is necessary in order to provide services you have requested (for example, sending your order or processing your donation), or where it is required by law.MarketingWe would like to send you emails about literacy news, our resources and training, and how you can support our work. We will only send this to you if you have given your consent. Once you have consented, you may opt out at any time and stop receiving these emails.We do not sell or share marketing data with any charities or other organisations.Access to your information and correctionYou have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of your personal information, please email contact@literacytrust.org.uk.We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date, so you may also ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate.CookiesCookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information. This information is used to track visitor use of our website and to compile statistical reports on website activity.You can set your browser not to accept cookies but this may mean some of our website features may not function as a result.More information is in our statement on how we use cookies.PasswordsWhere we have given you or you have chosen a password which enables you to access certain parts of our website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.Other websitesOur website contains links to other websites. This privacy policy only applies to this website so when you follow links to other websites you should read their privacy policies.Security of your informationYour data will be stored in a secure manner and we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that it cannot be accessed by unauthorised third parties.Use of your information outside of the European UnionIn order to provide the services you require, we may need to transfer your personal information to countries outside the EU, where different data protection rules apply. Where this is the case, we will ensure that the information is protected in accordance with this privacy policy.Retention periodWe will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity. For example, we will keep a record of donations subject to Gift Aid for at least seven years to comply with HMRC rules.If you request that we stop sending you marketing emails we will keep a record of your contact details and appropriate information to enable us to comply with your request not to be contacted by us.Changes to our privacy policyWe keep our privacy policy under regular review as data protection regulations are updated, and we will place any updates on this web page. This privacy policy was last updated on 21 May 2019.How to contact usIf you have any questions about our privacy policy or information we hold about you, please email contact@literacytrust.org.uk, call us on 020 7587 1842 or write to us at National Literacy Trust, 68 South Lambeth Road, London SW8 1RL.You also have the right to complain directly to the Information Commissioner’s Office if you are unhappy with how your data has been processed. See www.ico.org.uk.
Back to top
Share this article
Facebook
Twitter
Need a storyteller in the UK?
Search our listings
